<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Education | Whitewhim]]></title>
  <link href="http://whitewhim2718.github.com/blog/categories/education/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://whitewhim2718.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-06T23:41:19-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://whitewhim2718.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Whitewhim]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Troubles of a Small School]]></title>
    <link href="http://whitewhim2718.github.com/blog/2013/03/06/the-troubles-of-a-small-school/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-06T00:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://whitewhim2718.github.com/blog/2013/03/06/the-troubles-of-a-small-school</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Internships Are Necessary</h2>

<p>Now let me first preface this by saying that this is not an article about me complaining/whining about my inability to find a job. This is simply an analysis (albeit an evidently biased one) about some of the down sides of going to a small school. I will start off by saying that I love Mount Allison and that the professors, students and community are genuinely great. I have always been the type that has thrived in a small but tight knit community and this is simply the one for me. However, when it comes time for internships, co-op and summer jobs the Mount Allison program presents difficulties. At other schools in the area such as Memorial , Dalhousie and Saint Mary's they all provide very strong placement programs that help students find a relevant job in their field. This allows current and graduate students hugely valuable work experience coming out of school. In today's economy nearly all junior positions are listed as requiring 1-2 years of relevant experience in the workforce which is simply absurd considering these positions are traditionally meant for recent graduates. While this may be a by-product of the today's economy and a surplus of the qualified unemployed in the area it will in the long run hurt the economy as those recent graduates move elsewhere, however this is a topic for another time.</p>

<h2>No Placements </h2>

<p>Where Mount Allison fails is it's job placement. We have excellent educators and students to match them, in fact we have been ranked the top undergraduate university in Canada for 15 years in a row. I will say this with a true bias that Mount Allison deserves it, however the students also deserve better aid in obtaining employment. Without a coop program or job finder program Mount Allison makes it very tough for students to find a summer job an gain that valuable experience. Meanwhile students at other schools will pull ahead throughout the summer thanks to the aid they received. That is why I believe that Mount Allison needs to implement a job placement program at minimum and if they were truly proactive a coop program. This would allow the students at the school to continue to succeed in this hugely competitive work force and to allow the school to continue earning it's #1 rating</p>

<h2>No Change In Site </h2>

<p>Unfortunately I can't see this happening in the near future as it would take a lot of work and time just to get the ball moving on the program and university administrations are not known for their efficiency! In the mean time I guess all I can do is keep throwing my resume out there and hoping somebody bites!</p>

<p><em>-Whitewhim</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
